

CONTACT ME AT

144-77 Roosevelt Ave, Apt 1D, Flushing, NY 11354

david.cha225@gmail.com

https://davidcha.netlify.app/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/d
avid-taehyun-cha/

davidcha17@github.com

Medium Profile

Full-stack engineer experienced in React, JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails and fluent in CSS and HTML. Excellent in communicating, working independently, and collaborative work with distributed teams.

Background in the food industry, distribution, and management, focused on technical mastery, maximizing profits, workflow and efficiency, and client relations, Interested in creating content that will benefit the community in profound ways.

SKILLS

FRAMEWORKS

React

Ruby on Rails

CSS

Gatsby

Redux

PostgreSQL

Sinatra

LANGUAGES

JavaScript

HTML

Ruby

Java

SQL

DAVID CHA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROJECTS

Shop Tracker - Frontend | Website

Web app allows users to organize their current needs on a responsive platform.

- Implemented as a Vanilla Javascript Application to display the user's inputs.
- Utilized flexbox to make the application responsive and custom CSS to layout the S.P.A.
- Constructed an auto-save feature through local storage to prevent instance data from disappearing.

Portfolio - Website

A static website built to show recruiters and potential employers.

- Utilized Gatsby framework to create a React website.
- Customized CSS to integrate a trendy style for a portfolio.

Y.A.M.S - Frontend | Backend

Web app guide users towards the best foods based on their location.

- Integrated Fusion Yelp API to make calls for the surrounding restaurants near the user.
- Utilized the Mapbox API to display the user's location and all the restaurant's locations by applying states in React.
- Constructed user authentication by utilizing JWT.

Yap Station - Frontend | Backend

Collaborated project. Web app allows users to post status, comments, and photos.

- Implemented Carrier Wave to implement photo, posts, and video posts.
- Constructed user profiles where they can sign-in and look at their feeds and posts with JWT.
- Designed the web app with bootstrap and CSS.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operational Manager

O-Toro Inc. | Sept 2017 - Oct 2019

- Increased Company delivery output by 10% by constructing a consistent driving routine as a solution to increase client(s) satisfaction.
- Maintained client's satisfaction rate by mediating tensions between the company and clients.

School Teacher / Assistant Basketball Coach

Child Center of New York at I.S 237 | Oct 2015 - June 2016

- Constructed lesson plans and taught fundamentals of the care concepts to over 20 participants.
- Built stable connections with students and co-workers which gave rise to 25% in positive communication.
- Tutored algebra to sixth, seventh, and eighth graders which increased their math grade by at least 20%.

Assistant Coach

United States Tennis Association | June 2014 - Sept 2014

- Participated in the yearly world tournament by assisting player participants, sped up the tournament process by 5%.
- Focused on solidifying students' features which helped the majority of the class to move on to the next level class.

EDUCATION

The Flatiron School

Graduation Date May, 2020

Certificate of Completion

Queens College

Graduation Date May, 2018

Bachelors in Economics